Daniele Moltisanti

R&D Data Scientist - Machine Learning Engineer

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/daniele-moltisanti
Portfolio: https://daniele21.github.io
Email: danielemoltisanti@live.it
Contact: +39 3337337311

Profile

I'm a Data Scientist, Google Cloud Certified, passionate about making advantage of data for solving real case problems, through AI algorithms. Currently, Technical Manager of Conversational AI projects at Youtility Center. Experienced in developing ML/DL models from scratch, customizing them for outperforming in a specific business use cases. Mainly experienced in NLP algorithms and time-series forecasting related to finance.

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, Bash, Matlab, SQL, Java, C

- Tools: Git, Docker, Docker-Compose, Colab, Jupyter Notebook

- Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow 2.x, Keras, Rasa 2.x, Flask

- Libraries: Scikit-Learn, NLTK, Spacy, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Bokeh, OpenCV

- Soft Skills: Problem solving, Perseverance, Leadership, Cooperation

Work Experience

R&D Data Scientist

01/2021 - present Milan, Italy

Youtility Center S.p.A

- Managing Techical aspects of Conversational AI projects (chatbots).
- Achieved over 95% accuracy relative to NLU (natural language understanding) models.
- Achieved over 95% accuracy relative to NLG (natural language generation) models.
- Handled complex chatbot (more then 150 intents).
- Developing and managing the backend and the infrastructure needed for the conversational models.
- Developed multi-bot infrastructure, managing multiple bots inference in parallel.
- Developed multi-language and multi-domain chatbots.
- Making use of AWS services, such as storage (S3), laaS (EC2), database (Aurora).

Tools: Python, Tensorflow 2.x, AWS, Git, Rasa 2.x, Docker, NLTK, Spacy, SQL

• Data Scientist 05/2020 - 01/2021

Accenture S.p.A Milan, Italy

- Developed a custom NER model for the document understanding task related to Financial Industry, starting from a small dataset
- Achieved over 95% accuracy relative to the entity classification of documents, even if the small input data
- R&D relative to NLP tasks such as Entity Extraction and Named Entity Recognition (NER)
- Developed a custom Computer Vision denoising model for noise reduction in documents, achieving relevant improvements for the OCR task
- Developed projects making use of Google Cloud Platform (GCP) services, such as IaaS (compute instances), PaaS (app engine), storage

Tools: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow 2.x, Keras, CUDA, Git, OpenCV, Google Cloud Platform

Master Thesis Researcher

09/2019 - 04/2020

Politecnico di Milano Milan Mi

Title: "Anomaly Detection through Ganomaly: patch-wise training and transfer learning"

Goals: introducing improvements to the Ganomaly state-of-the-art for Anomaly Detection, in order to achieve an more efficent training for any-dimension images and a more effective performances through the trasfer learning technique

Tools: Python, Pytorch, CUDA, Git

Al Engineer - Internship

09/2018 - 02/2019

Reply S.p.A Milan, Italy

- Contributed in the development of a virtual assistant, where I developed the cognitive model for classifying fashion items in images.
- Experienced with IBM Watson services
- Integrated the cognitive model into the telegram channel, handling RestAPI

Tools: Python, Pytorch, CUDA, Git, IBM Watson

Education

•	Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering Politecnico di Milano	09/2019 - 04/2020 Milan, Italy
•	Athens Programme - course: From Complexity to Intelligence Telecom Paris-Tech	03/2019 - 03/2019 Paris, French
•	Erasmus project Universitat Politecnica de Valencia	01/2018 - 06/2018 Valencia, Spain
•	Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering Politecnico di Milano	09/2014 - 07/2017 Milan, Italy
Certifications		
•	Associate Cloud Engineer - Google Cloud Certification	10/2020
•	Spanish B2 level - FIDESCU	10/2017
•	English Toeic - ETS Global B.V.	09/2017
Courses		
•	Coursera	
	MLOps Fundamentals	03/2021
	Machine Learning for Trading Specialization	03/2021
	Sequence Models Specialization	05/2020
•	Qwiklabs	
	Sequence Models for Time Series and NLP on Google Cloud	12/2020
	Advanced ML: ML Infrastracture	09/2020
	Image Understanding with Tensorflow on GCP	11/2020

Personal Projects

• Finance Anomaly Detection | Python, Pytorch, Git, Pandas

11/2021 - present

- Nowcasting of financial time-series in order to detect anomalies.
- Anomaly labeling, Price analysis, Feature engineering on financial data
- Financial Sentiment Analysis | Python, Pytorch, Flask, Git, Pandas

09/2020 - 06/2021

- Developed an NLP engine for sentiment detection on news
- Developed a Client-Server architecture: the client side consists on a UI, developed with streamlit and the server side was developed with Flask API.

You can see all my personal projects on my portfolio